<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Khaled Boulbrachene</title>
    <link>https://KhaledBoulbrachene.github.io/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://KhaledBoulbrachene.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Khaled Boulbrachene</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>img/map[gravatar:%!s(bool=false) shape:circle]</url>
      <title>Khaled Boulbrachene</title>
      <link>https://KhaledBoulbrachene.github.io/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Structural Wind Analysis of The High-Rise Building 1180 Peachtree Using The Eurocode Standard and CFD Simulations</title>
      <link>https://KhaledBoulbrachene.github.io/project/wind/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://KhaledBoulbrachene.github.io/project/wind/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Wind Analysis of the high-rise building 1180 Peachtree, Atlanta, Georgia, US. Historical wind velocities for the previous 30 years were collected and an analytical aerostatic and aerodynamic analysis using the Eurocode was performed on the building. Then, a CFD simulation was done using KRATOS open-source project developed by the chair and CIMNE, a reseach center in Barcelona, Spain.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Implementation of an Immersed Boundary Method for a fourth-order Finite Volume Scheme, Master Thesis</title>
      <link>https://KhaledBoulbrachene.github.io/project/fv_ib/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://KhaledBoulbrachene.github.io/project/fv_ib/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Based on the work of 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.researchgate.net/publication/222652710_Compact_Fourth-Order_Finite-Volume_Method_for_Numerical_Solutions_of_Navier-Stokes_Equations_on_Staggered_Grids&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Arpiruk Hokpunna, 2010*&lt;/a&gt;, 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.researchgate.net/publication/222298105_An_Immersed_Boundary_Method_with_Direct_Forcing_for_the_Simulation_of_Particulate_Flows&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Markus Uhlmann, 2005*&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A second-order and fourth-order discretization schemes for the incompressible Navier-
Stokes equations on staggered grids are implemented. Two spatial dimensions are considered
and the discretizations are carried out for Cartesian uniform and non-uniform grids. Imple-
mentations are then verified and the order of accuracy of the adopted spatial and temporal
discretization schemes is validated. Next, an Immersed Boundary method (IBM) with a
direct forcing strategy is integrated with both flow solvers to simulate fluid-solid interac-
tion problems. The continuous IB method employs a smoothed approximation of the Dirac
delta function with a specific order of accuracy to smear (regularize) the immersed boundary
forces over the adjacent fluid cells. The accuracy of the solver then becomes dependent on
the order at which the coupling quantities are interpolated. In the literature, there exist dif-
ferent second-order regularized delta-function variants which are well-suited to use with the
second-order finite volume solver. However, an appropriate fourth-order regularized delta
function is not available and its detailed derivation is presented. At last, several numeri-
cal tests with smooth and non-smooth velocity fields are conducted to observe the rate of
convergence achieved of both IBM solvers.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Space-Time Finite Elements For 1D Heat Equation</title>
      <link>https://KhaledBoulbrachene.github.io/project/fcm/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://KhaledBoulbrachene.github.io/project/fcm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;An alternate method to model transient PDEs, where time is considered as a dimension, in contrast to the conventional transient FEM, where the space is discretized and a time intrgration scheme is applied. Thus, the 1D problem becomes 2D, and the shape functions are a tensor product of space and time. This approach is advntegous for its exponential convergence in time (when using high order shape functions), the ability to perform local time refinement, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Isogeometric analyis of trimmed membrane structures</title>
      <link>https://KhaledBoulbrachene.github.io/project/trimmed/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://KhaledBoulbrachene.github.io/project/trimmed/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The task was to extend a given code for the IGA of untrimmed membranes to the application of trimmed IGA. IGA uses the CAD information as an analysis model, instead of constructing a separate computational model. In order to get accurate results, a k-refinement is performed on the geometrical model. To represent complex geometries trimmed NURBS geometries are employed. In this present work, form finding is done on trimmed membrane surfaces. This project is implemented using MATLAB for the analysis and Rhino to define the geometries.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analytical Structural Design and a Feasibility Study of a Commercial-Residential Building Following the Standards of Kuwait</title>
      <link>https://KhaledBoulbrachene.github.io/project/bachelor/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://KhaledBoulbrachene.github.io/project/bachelor/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;An analytical structural design of an eco-friendly commercial-residential building in a vacant area in Jabriya, Kuwait. In addition, a feasibility study was established to determine the Pay Back Period of such a project. First, we start with an established soil report of the empty area to choose the structural system, and approximate loads of the building to determine the dimensions of each structural element following the ACI and ASCE standards. Then, a total cost estimation is done using a complete bill of quantity with a task timetable schedule.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
